[Music]
Welcome to the new busy central launch
edition busy central 2025 release wave
2. Today we will talk about new
clearance model in e documents. My name
is Alexander to product manager u
responsible for this functionality and I
have my colleague with me today. Yeah.
Hi.
>> So let's switch to this functionality.
Um first let's explain business values
about clearance model in uh e documents.
Clearance model was something we missed
when we deliver this functionality. This
is new framework and we had some time to
stabilize to create and now we are
trying to complete all missing parts to
work properly. So first reason is
regulatory compliance by design in a
situation and many countries require
that when you need to have pre-approved
by tax authorities or some other third
party partners your invoice it will be
enabled by default into this system. So
further it will streamline accurate
invoicing. So it will uh uh reduce your
manual effort for lots and third part
this is now ready for global
localizations. What does it mean? uh
this is now in a framework very similar
as we had for other e document features
this is framework this is not by default
localized so on top of that we will
start to build localizations such a
verifactory in Spain CFDI in Mexico
India invoicing so on so on
so traditionally before this wave we
supported multiorder model what does it
mean in general this is four corner
model but in some race situation it can
be used for five corner models as well.
So there is no any differences how you
can set up. So it can be supported three
corners, four corners, five corners
models but clearance model is different.
It require different architecture. So
process is
process foundational process this is
different. So we have send and receiver
and we have government or some other
authorities uh place where you will
validate your invoices. So how it's
going? First you need to send your
invoice to government or some other
authorities depends tax authorities for
clearance. So what does it mean? They
will check if everything is correct
related to regulation local regulation
in moment when everything is okay they
will send uh you back information and it
can be some QR code it can be some good
whatever it depends from localization to
localization and now you will have this
embedded clearing into invoice. When you
have this embedded into your invoice,
you can send to receiver. You can send
directly via email or eventually you can
use some of existing connectors and to
send via sender access point. So this is
on you how you will send and very often
it depends from country to country uh
what is required but you have all these
options on a desk.
But again let's focus this is mainly
what clearance model means. You need to
send to government your invoice to clear
and you get it back embedded clearing
model to send to your receiver any model
you want. One more feature exists or
will exist in this model. Currently this
is not supported. This is something what
we will deliver in the future to fully
support clearance model is validation as
a receiver. Currently yes you will get
uh documents everything is okay. But if
you want to validate against this
government office, this is something
what should be delivered on top of this
framework as well.
And one more thing I mentioned you can
be connected with the government or
through third party services. So it
supports sender access point receiver
access point as well. So both of models
are supported. This is only how you will
set up your service what you will choose
as a access point endpoint actually.
So what do you need to do? How to set
up? Actually you need to do two things
to set up your e document services and
workflow. But you can see three types
here. So first e document first e
document service for clearance and then
second e document service for sending to
your customers. And on the end you need
to set a workflow to orchestrate all
these previous two uh setups.
So when you create workflow you have a
template you can use workflow use uh
template to create and then you will see
how you can orchestrate communication
with those services you can uh set up uh
which will be first service second
service. So Benji will show you in a in
his demo. So Benji will now show full
end to end scenario how you can send uh
for clearance how you can provide
further to customer and also what is in
the setup. Reggie.
>> Yeah, thanks Aenda. I will take over. So
first let's navigate to the e document
service page.
Here you can find uh two services are
defined. The first one is a clearance
service and another one is a provider
service. For the clearance service as
mentioned earlier uh for different
countries it could be virus. So um if
you have some special equipment you can
always implement a new PT by yourself
then let's go to the key point of this
framework workflow.
Uh yeah here for this workflow uh you
can find there are five steps are
defined here. The first when the e
document is created uh this workflow
will be triggered and then it will
export document uh using the setup of
clearance uh service then it will be um
sent to the clearance service. Once it's
successfully sent it will be exported uh
using the setup of provider service. uh
then again if it's uh exported
successfully it will be sent to the
provider service. Finally uh if you need
you can also choose to send it to the uh
customer through the email. So in this
way you can see it's uh a workflow based
framework to ensure the flexibility.
Then uh I will show you how to use it in
bin center. here. Uh let's navigateate
to the sales invoice.
Yeah, let's choose a random uh sales
invoice and then post it.
Okay, now it's successfully posted. Then
let's open the corresponding e document
page. Here you can see
uh in this ed page uh there are two
service one is the clearance service and
another one is a provider service and
the status of the clearance service now
it's pending response it means when the
sales invoice it's posted the workflow
is triggered and then being sent to send
a send a request to the clearance
service now it's waiting for the
response from the clearance service
uh in the real world it will take se
several hours to get the response from
clearance service but uh for this smoke
it only take uh seconds so let's reopen
this page I think we already get the
response uh yeah here we go we already
get the response from the clearance
service then the status is changed to
the cleared and uh then the prov uh for
the provider service is also sent
yeah then let's get go back to the
proess invoice because for some uh for
some clearance service it will return a
QR code. So in the process uh in the
posted sales invoice we support you to
uh view QR code. Finally the customer
will receive an email with an
attachment.
Yeah, here in the attachment you can see
the QR code is also included in the
email. Yeah, that's all. Thanks.
>> Thank you.
>> Yeah, so you could see how it works. I
just wanted to uh mention this clearance
service we have in the background. This
is not something exist in a business
central. So you need to uh if you
localize if you're building your
localization you need to build this by
yourself because it depends from
localization to localization. This is
just example we created this service in
the background to show you how it works
in a practice. What is important for
next steps localizations this is as I
said this is just a framework. Our base
idea was to support the most global
requirements. Um probably maybe or
probably we will uh continue to improve
this model if something new appear. But
again keep in mind this is a framework.
So this is in this moment this is not
localized.
So to unlock other localization this
framework was necessary and now we will
continue to build localization on top of
this e document framework with the
cleaners model missing uh countries from
Microsoft localizations. actually not
missing countries. We already have
electronic voicing based on uh old model
in India and Mexico but now we will
start planning how to migrate Indian and
Mexican e voicing to new e documents
format and verifact 2 in Spain as well.
So this is something what we will do as
a Microsoft. Now we will bring uh
step-by-step uh our localization on a
top of uh e documents framework with a
clearance model and this is something
now what is ready for uh partner based
localization. So there is a dozen
countries all around the world
especially especially in um many
countries I think in a lot of countries
almost all models are uh preclarance
model. So many countries require this
model. This is something what really
important for
uh starting using e documents as a
framework globally.
Okay. Uh before I close this session, I
would like to emphasize please look into
these URLs. You can find many
interesting general resources for
business central. I will also encourage
you to subscribe on LinkedIn um uh on
our Microsoft LinkedIn so you can uh
follow our weekly news all announcements
on one place so easily to track and
watch more videos on YouTube akamsbc
YouTube you can find this video as well
but there only with e documents you will
have three or four additional videos
with e documents and some other topics
not only for this edition but for
previous editions as well. So thank you
for watching this session.
>> Thank you.